climatesaverscomputing.org 2007-12-12

# Climate Savers Computing - Privacy Policy

|  |  |   
---|---  
|  | 

|   
---  
|  | | CLIMATE SAVERS COMPUTING INITIATIVE   
Privacy Policy  
---  

Climate Savers Computing Initiative (“CSCI”) respects your privacy choices. We will limit the amount of information we ask of you to what is necessary and will treat it according to this privacy policy.   

CSCI encourages you to read this privacy policy and those of all web sites you visit.   
   
WEB HOSTING:   
   
Our site is developed, hosted and maintained by a third party who has access to all information on this site. This third party is responsible for maintaining the privacy described in this statement. The third party retains no rights or privileges associated with the information (i.e. cannot distribute, sell, exchange the information collected).  
   
REGISTRATION AND PERSONAL INFORMATION:  
   
In general, when you visit our website, you do not have to disclose any personally information. Personal information means any information that identifies an individual, including, but not limited to, a first and last name, a home or other physical address and an email address or other contact information, whether at work or at home. Before we ask you for personally information, we will explain how this information will be used and with whom we will share it. Our site requires registration to post/edit personal information, although typically all that's requested is your name, title, an e-mail address, and phone number.  
   
There are occasions where we will ask for information. We do this to be able to better understand your needs, and provide you with services that we believe may be valuable to you. Some examples of additional information our website may request are name, address and phone number. We give you the opportunity to elect not to receive information from us regarding upcoming events and other news. If you choose not to provide personal information that we request, then we may not be able to provide certain services or information to you.  
   
We also collect information from you when you contact us through our Contact page. We will collect your name and email address in order to follow up on your requests. You may also opt-in to receive updates regarding press releases and events. All we require is your email address and we will send you an email to confirm your subscription.  
   
SECURITY MEASURES:   
   
We will not collect personal information from you other than what you supply us on a voluntary basis. CSCI stores no information about the visitors to its web site except for information regarding the manner in which the site is used. We use information regarding the manner in which the web site is used only to improve the web site and the content quality. CSCI will not display or make available personal information that is not otherwise publicly available. CSCI processes personal information on our servers in the United States of America and in other countries. In some cases, we may process personal information on a server outside your own country.   
   
We protect the personal information you share with us. Access to your personal information is limited to people who need it to do their job. We will not disclose your personal information to any third party without receiving your permission.  
   
CSCI shares personal information with other companies or individuals outside of CSCI only in the following limited circumstances:  

  * We have your consent. We require opt-in consent for the sharing of any sensitive personal information.
  * We provide such information to our subsidiaries, affiliated companies or other trusted businesses or persons for the purpose of processing personal information on our behalf. We require that these parties agree to process such information based on our instructions and in compliance with this policy and any other appropriate confidentiality and security measures.
  * We have a good faith belief that access, use, preservation or disclosure of such information is reasonably necessary to: (a) satisfy any applicable law, regulation, legal process or enforceable governmental request, (b) enforce applicable terms of service, including investigation of potential violations thereof, (c) detect, prevent, or otherwise address fraud, security or technical issues, or (d) protect against imminent harm to the rights, property or safety of CSCI, its members, or the public as required or permitted by law. 

If CSCI becomes involved in an assignment, merger, acquisition, or any form of sale of some or all of its assets, we will provide notice before personal information is transferred and becomes subject to a different privacy policy.  

We may share with third parties certain pieces of aggregated, non-personal information, such as the number of users who visited a certain part of our site, for example, or how many users clicked on a particular link. Such information does not identify you individually.  
   
LINKED WEB SITES:   
   
We provide links to third party sites. Since we do not control these web sites, we encourage you to review the privacy policies posted on these (and all) third party sites. CSCI is not responsible for the privacy practices of those sites and cannot be held liable for any use of private data that they may create.   
   
COOKIES AND OTHER TRACKING TECHNOLOGIES:   
   
Some of our web pages utilize "cookies" and other tracking technologies. A "cookie" is a small text file that may be used, for example, to collect information about web site activity. Some cookies and other technologies may serve to recall personal information previously indicated by a visitor to the site. Most browsers allow you to control cookies, including whether or not to accept them and how to remove them.  
   
You may set most browsers to notify you if you receive a cookie, or you may choose to block cookies with your browser, but please note that if you choose to erase or block your cookies, you will need to re-enter your original user ID and password to gain access to certain parts of the site.  
   
Tracking technologies may record information such as Internet domain and host names; Internet protocol (IP) addresses; browser software and operating system types; clickstream patterns; and dates and times that our site is accessed. Our use of cookies and other tracking technologies allows us to improve our site and your experience visiting our site. We may also analyze information that does not contain personal information for trends and statistics.  
   
CHILDREN’S PRIVACY:   
   
We do not knowingly collect personal information from children under the age of 13. If we learn that we have personal information on a child under the age of 13, we will delete that information from our systems.  
   
ACCESSING AND UPDATING INFORMATION:   
   
We need your help in making sure your personal information is correct in our systems. Please notify us of changes to your name, address, title, phone number or email address.  
   
UNSUBSCRIBING:   
   
Each email newsletter has instructions on how to unsubscribe.  
   
POLICY UPDATES:   
   
All updates to this policy will be posted here.  
   
CONTACTING THE WEB SITE:   
   
If you have any questions about this privacy statement, the practices of this site, or your dealings with this Web site, you can contact the Site Administrator at  [admin@climatesaverscomputing.org](mailto:admin@climatesaverscomputing.org).  

|   
---  
| You have the power to make  
a difference  
---  
[Pledge your support](http://www.climatesaverscomputing.org/program/pledge.html) to slow global warming, one power-efficient computer at a time.  
| **54**  
**MILLION** | By 2010 we seek to reduce global CO2 emissions from the operation of computers by 54 million tons per year.[1](http://www.climatesaverscomputing.org/program/privacy.html#f1)  
---|---  
| Did You Know?  
---  
“The United States, with only four percent of the world’s population, is responsible for 22% of the world’s greenhouse gas emissions.”[2](http://www.climatesaverscomputing.org/program/privacy.html#f2)  
   
|    
---  
   
|    
---  
   
© 2007 Climate Savers Computing Initiative.  
Climate Savers® is a trademark or registered trademark of WWF, the international conservation organization. Used under license.   
|   |  | 1Based on IDC projections of desktop and server units shipped, a baseline of typical desktop and server power consumption in the first half of 2007, and an average power cost of $0.0885/kWh.  
---  
2Source: StopGlobalWarming.org. [View article](http://www.stopglobalwarming.org/).  
|
